1. Demonstrate identifying duplicates in a table, and deletion of those using below table
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
		test
	t		t1
	--		--
	1		3
	1		2
	1		4
	1		3
	1		3
	1		4
	1		5


   identifying duplicate from above table:
------------------------------------------

 postgres=# select * from test group by (t, t1) having count(*) >1;   -----------> here duplicates means, both columns (t, t1) should be same values. 
 

 t | t1
---+----
 1 |  3
 1 |  4
(2 rows)

  Deletion of duplicate in a table:
-----------------------------------
Before we going to do deletion, we need to know about one hidden column(ctid).

PostgreSQL has another hidden key for every record, and that is the ctid. The ctid field is a field that exists in every PostgreSQL table and is unique for each record in a table and denotes the location of the tuple. 

example:
--------

  postgres=# select t, t1, ctid from test;
 t | t1 |  ctid
---+----+--------
 1 |  2 | (0,2)
 1 |  5 | (0,7)
 1 |  3 | (0,8)
 1 |  3 | (0,9)
 1 |  3 | (0,10)
 1 |  4 | (0,11)
 1 |  4 | (0,12)
(7 rows) 

step1: create unlogged table with duplicate records from test.

 create unlogged table dup_test as select t, t1, min(ctid) min_ctid from test group by (t, t1) having count(*) > 1;
SELECT 2

postgres=# select * from dup_test;
 t | t1 | min_ctid
---+----+----------
 1 |  3 | (0,8)
 1 |  4 | (0,11)
(2 rows)

step2: delete duplicate records using dup_test table except old duplicate record.

 delete from test using dup_test where test.t=dup_test.t and test.t1=dup_test.t1 and test.ctid != dup_test.min_ctid;
DELETE 3
 
postgres=# select * from test;
 t | t1
---+----
 1 |  2
 1 |  5
 1 |  3
 1 |  4
(4 rows)


 

2. Demonstrate the usage of work_mem parameter by simulating joins on large tables.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

     If we ran a join sql query on big tables, it will take lot of run time. So if you want to reduce the query run time, then increase the work_mem for that query.

example:
--------
   I have two big tables names are big, dup_big usig these two tables i will run a join sql query.

Now iam going to run the same query with different "work_mem".

work_mem="50MB":

postgres=# delete from big using dup_big where big.t=dup_big.t and big.ctid != dup_big.min_ctid;
DELETE 5000000
Time: 114793.609 ms
postgres=# show work_mem ;


work_mem="128MB":

postgres=# delete from big using dup_big where big.t=dup_big.t and big.ctid != dup_big.min_ctid;
DELETE 5000000
Time: 27382.210 ms
postgres=# show work_mem ;

 
NOTE: If u absorve the above both query times, first one tooks approx 115 sec  and second one tooks just  28 sec approx. Because 1st query work_mem=50MB and 2nd query work_mem=128MB.     


3. Demonstrate the usage of TEMP tables
---------------------------------------

TEMP tables means TEMPORARY tables.
 
A temporary table, as its named implied, is a short-lived table that exists for the duration of a database session. PostgreSQL automatically drops the temporary tables at the end of a session or a transaction. 

EXAMPLE:
--------

postgres=# create temp table ball(t int);
CREATE TABLE
postgres=# insert into ball values (1);
INSERT 0 1
postgres=# select * from ball;
 t
---
 1
(1 row)

postgres=# \q
 postgres@localhost:- psql                                                                                                                                          ✔ 
postgres=# select * from ball;
ERROR:  relation "ball" does not exist
LINE 1: select * from ball;
                      ^



4. Demonstrate the usage of LOCK TABLE IN SHARE ROW EXLUSIVE MODE, and also define all other possible lock modes (Read PostgreSQL manual)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 
SHARE ROW EXLUSIVE MODE: It is a table level lock. 
-----------------------
we lock the table in order to prevent any INSERT, UPDATE or DELETE operations


TABLE LEVEL LOCK MODES:
------------------------


ACCESS SHARE
------------

Conflicts with the ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock mode only.
The SELECT command acquires a lock of this mode on referenced tables. In general, any query that only reads a table and does not modify it will acquire this lock mode.

ROW SHARE
---------

Conflicts with the EXCLUSIVE and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes.
The SELECT FOR UPDATE and SELECT FOR SHARE commands acquire a lock of this mode on the target table(s) (in addition to ACCESS SHARE locks on any other tables that are referenced but not selected FOR UPDATE/FOR SHARE).

ROW EXCLUSIVE
-------------

Conflicts with the SHARE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes.
The commands UPDATE, DELETE, and INSERT acquire this lock mode on the target table (in addition to ACCESS SHARE locks on any other referenced tables). In general, this lock mode will be acquired by any command that modifies data in a table.

SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE
----------------------

Conflicts with the SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE, SHARE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes. This mode protects a table against concurrent schema changes and VACUUM runs.
Acquired by VACUUM (without FULL), ANALYZE, CREATE INDEX CONCURRENTLY, and ALTER TABLE VALIDATE and other ALTER TABLE variants (for full details see ALTER TABLE).

SHARE
-----

Conflicts with the ROW EXCLUSIVE, SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes. This mode protects a table against concurrent data changes.
Acquired by CREATE INDEX (without CONCURRENTLY).

SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE
-------------------

Conflicts with the ROW EXCLUSIVE, SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE, SHARE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes. This mode protects a table against concurrent data changes, and is self-exclusive so that only one session can hold it at a time.
This lock mode is not automatically acquired by any PostgreSQL command.

EXCLUSIVE
---------

Conflicts with the ROW SHARE, ROW EXCLUSIVE, SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE, SHARE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock modes. This mode allows only concurrent ACCESS SHARE locks, i.e., only reads from the table can proceed in parallel with a transaction holding this lock mode.
Acquired by REFRESH MATERIALIZED VIEW CONCURRENTLY.

ACCESS EXCLUSIVE
----------------

Conflicts with locks of all modes (ACCESS SHARE, ROW SHARE, ROW EXCLUSIVE, SHARE UPDATE EXCLUSIVE, SHARE, SHARE ROW EXCLUSIVE, EXCLUSIVE, and ACCESS EXCLUSIVE). This mode guarantees that the holder is the only transaction accessing the table in any way.
Acquired by the DROP TABLE, TRUNCATE, REINDEX, CLUSTER, VACUUM FULL, and REFRESH MATERIALIZED VIEW (without CONCURRENTLY) commands. Many forms of ALTER TABLE also acquire a lock at this level (see ALTER TABLE). This is also the default lock mode for LOCK TABLE statements that do not specify a mode explicitly.


Tip: Only an ACCESS EXCLUSIVE lock blocks a SELECT (without FOR UPDATE/SHARE) statement.


5. What is a sequence in PostgreSQL(google)
--------------------------------------------

